Joshua Tracy

Tampa, FL

352-428-5425





Github: https://josh-tracy.github.io/



Networking professional holding a TS/SCI clearance with 3 years in networking and related IT fields. Demonstrated abilities installing, administering, and configuring enterprise networks and remote LANS, as well as deploying infrastructure in AWS and automation with Ansible.

Qualifications & Certifications

TS/SCI Security clearance

Cisco Certified Network Professional Route and Switch (CCNP)

Cisco Certified Design Associate (CCDA)

Cisco Certified Network Associate – Security (CCNA-Security) DoD 8570

Amazon Web Services Certified Solutions Architect - Associate (AWS)

CompTIA Security+

CompTIA Project+

LPI Linux Essentials

Experience

From Sept. 2019 – Present

Enterprise Network Engineer / United States Special Operations Command – Tampa, FL

- Part of the SOCOM Innovations team responsible for research and implementation of new technologies within the SOCOM IT infrastructure.
- Experience deploying containerized instances for applications.
- Part of DevOps team responsible for implementing a PaaS solution using Amazon Web Services EC2, S3, Git Lab, and Ansible automation.
- Manage the on-premise developer network using Cisco ACI and Nexus switches.
- Work with vendors, the Government, carriers and technical staff on implementing new network solutions, optimization, and ongoing management.

From Sept 2018 - Sept 2019

Enterprise Network Administrator LAN/WAN / United States Special Operations Command – Tampa, FL

- Provide Tier 1/2 support for remote sites located around the globe. Troubleshooting includes router, switch, and ASA configurations and KG-250 encryption devices.
- Troubleshoot issues relating to DMVPN, EIGRP, DHCP, VLANs, and ACLs.
- Implement approved configurations changes on the LAN/WAN to include subnet size modifications, Cisco VOIP phone configurations, and ACL modifications.
- Upgrade Cisco device firmware and operating systems.
- Monitor the enterprise network via Solarwinds 24/7 for network device and transport outages around the globe.

From Feb 2018 - July 2018

IT Helpdesk Technician / United States Special Operations Command - Tampa, FL

- Incident manager on shift responsible for triaging high priority / emergency incidents and outages, escalating them to proper technical leads within the enterprise.
- Interface directly with supported end-users to provide hardware, software, network, and application problem resolution.
- Modify / create and troubleshoot user accounts in Active Directory, submit changes and trouble tickets via Remedy ticketing system.
- Serve as the initial point of contact for resolution of desktop/mobile/and laptop related issues in a 56,000+ customer enterprise.

From Sept. 2016 - Sept 2019

Cyber Systems Operations Journeyman / 290th JCSS, Florida Air National Guard – Tampa, FL

- Install, configure, and operate NIPR and SIPR networks and communications satellites in response to state emergencies and federal needs.
- Implement and maintain a mobile COTS LAN consisting of Cisco routers, switches, ESXi hosts, and VoIP phones.
- Manage system account using group policy objects and remote management.

From Sept. 2010 – Sept. 2016

Aircraft Electrical and Environmental Systems Technician / 116th AMX Squadron - Warner Robins, GA

- Troubleshoot, inspect, repair, and maintain over 15 different electrical and environmental systems on 3 different aircraft.
- Test various aircraft parts to ensure proper specifications are met.
- Utilize documentation, wiring diagrams, and schematics to complete tasks and troubleshoot.

Education

Currently in pursuit of 118 / 122 credits completed:

Bachelor of Science: Network Operations and Security

Western Governors University

Skills

• DMVPN	• EIGRP/ RIPv2	•DHCP
•Infoblox IP Management System	•Windows	•Solarwinds
•Trouble Ticket System	•Type 1 Encryption devices	•Cisco IOS
•Cisco Call Manager / IP Phones	•TACACS	•Routing / Switching
•Ansible	•AWS	•Linux
• Git	• Containers	